Guide to the Raymond Philip Morris Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
Raymond Philip Morris Papers
1923-1994
RG 80
Yale University Divinity School Library
7.5
(16 boxes)
The papers document Morris's long professional career as head librarian of the Yale Divinity School Library and prominent leader in the field of theological librarianship. Raymond Philip Morris (1904-1990) was head librarian of the Yale Divinity School Library from1932 to 1972.
Morris, Raymond P.
Conditions Governing Access
Open to qualified researchers.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of the Morris family.
Biographical / Historical
1904 Mar 16 Born in Garnett, Kansas to Charles Elmer and Margaret Ann (Riley) Morris
1926 B.A. Baker University
1928 Married Jean Louise Kelly (Children: Thelma Jean, Marcia Louise, Raymond Philip)
1929 B.D. Garrett Biblical Institute
1930 B.S. Columbia University
1931-1932 Librarian, Garrett Biblical Institute
1932 M.S. Columbia University
1932-1934 Assistant Librarian, Yale Divinity School
1934-1972 Librarian, Yale Divinity School
1941-1949 Assistant Professor of Religious Literature, Yale Divinity School
1949-1951 Associate Professor, Yale Divinity School
1951 M.A. (honorary) Yale University
1951-1972 Professor, Yale Divinity School
1952 D.Litt. Baker University
1965 D.D. Drake University
1990 Oct 21 Died
Scope and Contents
These papers date primarily from 1955 to 1975 and document Morris's long professional career
career as head librarian of the Yale Divinity School Library and prominent leader in the field of theological librarianship. The materials in this collection were selected for inclusion by Morris.
Series I, Correspondence, includes five folders of family correspondence. The remainder is general correspondence with librarians, faculty members, funding agencies, and church leaders. Morris was a widely known advisor for theological libraries and this role is reflected in the correspondence. Additional correspondence related to specific projects and committees is contained in Series III.
Series II, Writings, contains articles, papers, sermons, and addresses by Morris. Most of Morris's writings dealt with theological education and libraries. Though not ordained, Morris was an active member of the Methodist Church and frequently gave sermons in area churches. Also of interest are the various tributes to Yale Divinity School faculty that Morris delivered at memorial services for them.
Series III includes representative documentation of Morris's involvement in various facets of theological education and librarianship. Documentation of Morris's work with the American Theological Library Association is supplemented by YDSL Record Group No. 81, Records of the ATLA Library Development Project. Documentation related to the China Records Project and the Yale Divinity School Library is supplemented by YDSL Record Group No. 92, Archives of the Yale Divinity School Library. Files relating to the Divinity School are complemented by records in YDSL Record Group No. 53, Yale Divinity School Memorabilia. Materials on the Mott Biography Project are related to documentation of biographer C. Howard Hopkins in the John R. Mott Papers, YDSL Record Group No. 45.
Series IV, Biographical Material, provides a small glimpse into the personal life and warm personality of Raymond P. Morris. Of particular interest are five audio cassette tapes, which include reminiscences of Jean Morris. Circular letters from the Morrises, found in Series I, also provide biographical documentation.
Arrangement
I. Correspondence
II. Writings
III. Professional Activities/Committees/Projects
IV. Biographical Material
Theological libraries -- United States; Librarians; Morris, Raymond P.; American Theological Library Association; Yale University. Divinity School. Library -- History
- Correspondence, Series I
  - A - D (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Allen, Yorke Jr., 1959-1984 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bailey, J. Russell, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Bainton, Roland - re. beginning position as Librarian at YDS, 1932 (Box 15, Folder 204)
  - Baker University, 1967-1982 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Beach, Robert F., 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Cohen, George, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Diehl, Katherine S., 1960-1962 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Drake University (re: honorary degree), 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Eiselen, Dr. Frederick Carl, 1932-1933 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - English, Dr. John, 1973-1977 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - F - L (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Kelly, Beulah, 1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Keogh, Andrew, 1932 (Box 15, Folder 205)
  - King, Dr. Rachel, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - M - P (includes Paul Minear and Liston Pope) (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - May, Mark (letter from RPM re. taking position at YDS), 1932 (Box 15, Folder 205)
  - McCord, James I., 1966,1976 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Michaelson, Robert (includes letter to Mrs. H. Richard Niebuhr), 1974 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Morris, Jean and Marcia to RPM, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Morris, RP to Jean and family, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Morris, RP to Jean and family, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Morris, Thelma, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Morris, Thelma - letters to family re. events honoring RPM and reminiscences re ATLA Board of Microtext, 1982 (Box 15, Folder 203)
  - Morris - various extended family, 1960-1969,1982 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Morris - circular letters, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Myers, Rev. Charles D., 1977 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Newhall, Dr. Jannette E., 1958-1968 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Niebuhr, Richard R., 1978 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Peterson, Stephen L., 1970-1982 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - R - S (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Sarah Marquis Travel Service, 1958-1959 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Schubert, Dorothy (re: Schubert book collection), 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Songco, Socorro, 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - T - V (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Union Theological Seminary (while RPM was in the Philippines), 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Union Theological Seminary, 1950, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - University of Notre Dame (Includes: Albert L. Schlitzer and James T. Burtchaell), 1965-1969 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Vieth, Paul and Verna, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - W - Y (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Weigle, Luther ( re. position as Librarian at Yale Divinity School), 1932 (Box 15, Folder 202)
  - Yale Divinity School Library staff, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - first name only (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Writings, Series II
  - Articles/ Papers/ Books
    - "Christian Inalienable Rights", n.d. (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - "Church, Its Orders and Sacraments according to the Anglicanism of John Wesley", after 1962 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - "Current trends in Religious Thought and Literature" for ALA Round Table., 1950 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - "The Good Book in Religion", 1953 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - "Implications for the Renewal of the Church for Theological Libraries: A Protestant Appraisal.", 1967 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Memories of Roland Bainton, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - "Library Standards for Graduate Theological Work"-draft (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Council for Theological Education - draft manuscript, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - "Of Books and Learning", ca. 1955 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - A Preliminary and Tentative listing of Books of Christian Theological Institutions in South-East Asia compiled by RPM, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - "Renovations in a Crowded Cloister" in The Pioneer, 1955 (Box 15, Folder 200)
    - "Revised Standard Version of the New Testament" (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - "Some Impressions of the Libraries in Protestant Theological Institutions in Southeast Asia and their implications for the Christian Church." (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - "Study of the Library facilities of the Boston University School of Theology.", 1932 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - "Theological Librarianship as a Ministry" in Yale Divinity News, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - "Theology: in Transition, in Interlude", 1966 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - A Theological Book List by RPM, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - A Theological Book List - "An exact reprint of the 1960 text with a revised and enlarged index" - Published for The Theological Education Fund, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 198)
    - "Why Dominie Doesn't Read", 1965 (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - "Yale and the English Bible" (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Review: Fellowship of Saints by T. Kepler, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Review: Name of God by P. Crawford, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Review: Dr. William's Library by Dr. Williams, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - unidentified review, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - miscellaneous manuscripts; untitled, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Sermons/ Addresses
    - Sermons, 1944-1953 (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Sermons, 1954-1960 (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Sermons, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - Sermons, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - Sermons, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - Sermon fragments and miscellaneous sermon material (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - Worship service bulletins (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - Prayers, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - Luther Weigle memorial address, 1976 Sep 9 (Box 4, Folder 57)
    - L. Weigle honorary degree by Standard Bible Committee, 1966 Feb 1 (Box 4, Folder 57)
    - Clarence Shedd memorial service, 1973 Dec 1 (Box 4, Folder 58)
    - Biblical Seminary in New York, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 59)
    - Episcopal Theological Seminary in the Southwest - commencement address, 1964 May 19 (Box 4, Folder 60)
    - Episcopal Theological School, Massachusetts - convocation address, 1966 Oct (Box 4, Folder 61)
    - Silliman College, Philippines - Honors Day address and 'Librarianship as Ministry' talk, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 62)
    - Paul Minear: Yale Divinity School Shaffer Lectures - introduction, 1974 Feb (Box 4, Folder 63)
    - Douglas Clyde Macintosh - reflections on the life of, 1980 Feb 13 (Box 4, Folder 64)
    - Ruth Bainton memorial service, 1966 May 15 (Box 4, Folder 65)
    - Robert Calhoun memorial service, 1983 Sep 28 (Box 4, Folder 66)
    - Liston Pope memorial service, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 67)
    - Miscellaneous addresses, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 68)
  - Unpublished writings
    - "A Study of the Library Facilities of a Group of Representative Protestant Theological Seminaries in the United States and Canada" - submitted in partial fulfillment of the requirements for the degree of Master of Science in the School of Library Service, Columbia University, 1932 (Box 15, Folder 196)
    - "A Preliminary and Tentative Listing of Books for the Libraries of Christian Theological Education in Southeastern Asia" - compiled for The Nanking Board of Founders, 1958++ (Box 15, Folder 197)
- Professional Activities, Committees Projects, Series III
  - American Association of Theological Schools - accreditation information, 1965-1966 (Box 5, Folder 69)
  - American Association of Theological Schools - G. W. Webber committee and proposal, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 70)
  - American Association of Theological Schools - collected material (Box 5, Folder 71)
  - American Theological Library Association -"A Summary 1961-1966" report by RPM, 1967 Jun (Box 5, Folder 72)
  - American Theological Library Association-Board of Microtext, 1959, 1969-1974 (Box 5, Folder 73)
  - American Theological Library Association -Committee on Financial Assistance from Foundations, 1965-1972 (Box 5, Folder 74)
  - American Theological Library Association-Accreditation for Earlham School of Religion, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 75)
  - American Theological Library Association -Conference in Toronto, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 76)
  - American Theological Library Association-Correspondence to Catholic Seminary Librarians meeting, 1966-1967 (Box 5, Folder 77)
  - American Theological Library Association -Correspondence to theological schools: Austin Presbyterian to Wesley Theological Seminary, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 78)
  - American Theological Library Association-Correspondence to Dr. Jesse H. Ziegler at AATS, 1961, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 79)
  - American Theological Library Association-Correspondence to Elmer J. O'Brien at AATS, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 80)
  - American Theological Library Association-Correspondence to United Theological College, Bangalore, India, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 81)
  - American Theological Library Association -Funding from Sealantic Inc. (includes correspondence with Yorke Allen.), 1958-1960 (Box 5, Folder 82)
  - American Theological Library Association-Funding from Sealantic Inc., 1961-1976 (Box 5, Folder 83)
  - American Theological Library Association -Negro Theological Education, Interdenominational Theological Center in Atlanta. Includes letter to H. Richard Niebuhr, 1961-1962 (Box 6, Folder 84)
  - American Theological Library Association -Records and Payments to Institutions (Box 6, Folder 85)
  - American Theological Library Association -Library consultation program, 1972-1973 (Box 6, Folder 86)
  - American Association of Theological Schools -Proposals and Reports (Box 6, Folder 87)
  - American Theological Library Association -Published aids, 1965-1972 (Box 6, Folder 88)
  - American Theological Library Association Library Development Program - "Aids to a Theological Library - Selected Basic Reference Books and Periodicals", 1969 (Box 15, Folder 199)
  - China Records Project: Addresses (Box 6, Folder 89)
  - China Records Project: Correspondence - A (Box 6, Folder 90)
  - China Records Project: Correspondence - B (Box 6, Folder 91)
  - China Records Project: Correspondence - C (Box 6, Folder 92)
  - China Records Project: Correspondence - D - E (Box 6, Folder 93)
  - China Records Project: Correspondence - Erickson, Mrs. C. Telford (Box 7, Folder 102)
  - China Records Project: Correspondence - F - G (Box 7, Folder 94)
  - China Records Project: Correspondence - H (Box 7, Folder 95)
  - China Records Project: Correspondence - I - K (Box 7, Folder 96)
  - China Records Project: Correspondence - L (Box 7, Folder 97)
  - China Records Project: Correspondence - M - N (Box 7, Folder 98)
  - China Records Project: Correspondence - O (Box 7, Folder 99)
  - China Records Project: Correspondence - P - R (Box 7, Folder 100)
  - China Records Project: Correspondence - S (Box 7, Folder 101)
  - China Records Project: Correspondence - T - V (Box 7, Folder 103)
  - China Records Project: Correspondence - W (Box 7, Folder 104)
  - China Records Project: Correspondence - X - Z (Box 8, Folder 105)
  - Collected quotations, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 106)
  - Ecumenical Library Project, Evangelical Seminary of Puerto Rico, 1962-1968 (Box 8, Folder 107)
  - Institute for Ecumenical and Cultural Research -Board of Directors meetings, 1969-1972 (Box 8, Folder 108)
  - Institute for Ecumenical and Cultural Research -Board of Directors meetings, 1971 Jun (Box 8, Folder 109)
  - Institute for Ecumenical and Cultural Research -Board of Directors meetings, 1972 Jun (Box 8, Folder 110)
  - Institute for Ecumenical and Cultural Research -Board of Directors meetings, 1974 Oct (Box 8, Folder 111)
  - Institute for Ecumenical and Cultural Research -Board of Directors meetings, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 112)
  - Institute for Ecumenical and Cultural Research -Budgets and finance reports, 1968-1976 (Box 8, Folder 113)
  - Institute for Ecumenical and Cultural Research -Charles Grace Award, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 114)
  - Institute for Ecumenical and Cultural Research-Conference on the formation and transmission of values in society, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 115)
  - Institute for Ecumenical and Cultural Research -Constitutions and bylaws, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 116)
  - Institute for Ecumenical and Cultural Research -Correspondence, 1969-1971 Aug (Box 8, Folder 117)
  - Institute for Ecumenical and Cultural Research -Correspondence, 1971 Sep - 1972 Jan (Box 8, Folder 118)
  - Institute for Ecumenical and Cultural Research -Correspondence, 1972 Feb - Jul (Box 8, Folder 119)
  - Institute for Ecumenical and Cultural Research -Correspondence, 1972 Aug - Oct (Box 9, Folder 120)
  - Institute for Ecumenical and Cultural Research -Correspondence, 1972 Nov - 1973 Aug (Box 9, Folder 121)
  - Institute for Ecumenical and Cultural Research -Correspondence, 1973 Oct - 1976 (Box 9, Folder 122)
  - Institute for Ecumenical and Cultural Research -Executive committee meeting, 1969 Oct (Box 9, Folder 123)
  - Institute for Ecumenical and Cultural Research -Executive committee minutes. (includes report by RPM), 1970-1972 (Box 9, Folder 124)
  - Institute for Ecumenical and Cultural Research -Executive committee meeting, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 125)
  - Institute for Ecumenical and Cultural Research -Historical materials sent to RPM relating to personnel problems, 1971 Nov (Box 9, Folder 126)
  - Institute for Ecumenical and Cultural Research -Newsletters, occasional papers and miscellaneous documentation, 1970-1979 (Box 9, Folder 127)
  - Institute for Ecumenical and Cultural Research -Petition to Lilly Endowment, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 128)
  - Institute for Ecumenical and Cultural Research -Report to libraries of St. Benedict and St. John, Minnesota, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 129)
  - Institute for Ecumenical and Cultural Research -Search committee for Executive director, 1973-1974 (Box 9, Folder 130)
  - Institute for Ecumenical and Cultural Research -miscellaneous material (Box 9, Folder 131)
  - Library Consulting Projects -general correspondence, 1963-1966 (Box 9, Folder 132)
  - Library Consulting Projects -consulting manual from Library Management and Building Consultants, Inc. Evanston, Illinois (Box 9, Folder 133)
  - Library Consulting Projects -Andover Newton Theological School, Massachusetts, 1962-1963 Oct (Box 9, Folder 134)
  - Library Consulting Projects -Andover Newton Theological School, Massachusetts, 1963 Oct - 1966 (Box 10, Folder 135)
  - Library Consulting Projects -Bishop Tucker College, Mukono, Uganda, 1967 (Box 10, Folder 136)
  - Library Consulting Projects -Christian Theological Seminary, Indiana, 1961-1962 (Box 10, Folder 137)
  - Library Consulting Projects -Eden Theological Seminary, Missouri, 1963-1965 (Box 10, Folder 138)
  - Library Consulting Projects -Episcopal Theological Seminary of the Caribbean, 1965-1966 (Box 10, Folder 139)
  - Library Consulting Projects -Evangelical Seminary of Puerto Rico, 1962-1970 (Box 10, Folder 140)
  - Library Consulting Projects -Lancaster Theological Seminary, Pennsylvania, 1962-1963 (Box 10, Folder 141)
  - Library Consulting Projects -Lutheran School of Theology, Chicago, 1964-1965 (Box 10, Folder 142)
  - Library Consulting Projects -St. Patricks College and Seminary, Hartsdale, NY, 1963 (Box 10, Folder 143)
  - Library Consulting Projects -Union Theological Seminary, 1971-1972 (Box 10, Folder 144)
  - Library Consulting Projects -United Missionary Library, Interchurch Center, NY, 1977-1978 (Box 11, Folder 145)
  - Library Consulting Projects -White House Library, 1963 (Box 11, Folder 146)
  - Library Consulting Projects -World Council of Churches Library, 1962 (Box 11, Folder 147)
  - Missionary Research Library proposal, 1964-1966 Aug (Box 11, Folder 148)
  - Missionary Research Library proposal, 1966 Sep-1967 (Box 11, Folder 149)
  - Mott Biography Project - Correspondence, 1964-1965 (Box 11, Folder 150)
  - Mott Biography Project - Correspondence, 1966 (Box 11, Folder 151)
  - Mott Biography Project - Correspondence, 1967 (Box 11, Folder 152)
  - Mott Biography Project - Correspondence, 1968-1969 (Box 11, Folder 153)
  - Mott Biography Project - Correspondence, 1970-1972 (Box 12, Folder 154)
  - Mott Biography Project - Correspondence, 1973-1976 (Box 12, Folder 155)
  - Mott Biography Project - Correspondence, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 156)
  - Mott Biography Project - Correspondence, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 157)
  - Mott Biography Project - Correspondence, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 158)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities: consulting work, 1974-1977 (Box 12, Folder 159)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities: consulting work, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 160)
  - Yale University: Alumni fund, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 161)
  - Yale University: University Librarian Search, 1963-1967 (Box 12, Folder 162)
  - Yale Divinity School -Berkeley Divinity School merger, 1970-1972 (Box 12, Folder 163)
  - Yale Divinity School -Deanship search commitee, 1962-1963 (Box 13, Folder 164)
  - Yale Divinity School -Deanship search commitee, 1968-1969 (Box 13, Folder 165)
  - Yale Divinity School -Liston Pope memorial Reflection articles, 1972-1973 (Box 13, Folder 166)
  - Yale Divinity School -Ruth Bainton Memorial Fund, 1967-1970 (Box 13, Folder 167)
  - Yale Divinity School -Calhoun Festschrift, 1962-1964 (Box 13, Folder 168)
  - Yale Divinity School -YDS / Woodstock College proposal, 1965-1967 (Box 13, Folder 169)
  - Yale Divinity School Library -Annual Reports, 1966-1972 (Box 13, Folder 170)
  - Yale Divinity School Library -Berkeley Divinity School and library, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 171)
  - Yale Divinity School Library -Budgets, 1961-1964 (Box 13, Folder 172)
  - Yale Divinity School Library -meetings with Harvard, Union and Princeton librarians, 1969-1970 (Box 13, Folder 173)
  - Yale Divinity School Library -Letters of recommendation, Job openings, 1963-1967 (Box 13, Folder 174)
  - Yale Divinity School Library -Letters of recommendation, Job openings, 1968-1980 (Box 13, Folder 175)
  - Yale Divinity School Library -Report: Comparative study of resources, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 176)
  - Yale Divinity School Library -Ronald E. Diener proposals and projects, 1969-1971 (Box 13, Folder 177)
  - World Council of Churches library consulting work, 1955-1956 (Box 14, Folder 178)
  - Nanking Theological Seminary Board of Founders project on theological libraries in Asia -Trip by RPM to Asia, including SE Asia Theological Seminary Librarians Workshop in the Philippines, 19581-1961 (Box 14, Folder 179)
  - Nanking Theological Seminary Board of Founders project on theological libraries in Asia -Trip by RPM to Asia, including SE Asia Theological Seminary Librarians Workshop in the Philippines (Box 14, Folder 180)
  - Nanking Theological Seminary Board of Founders project on theological libraries in Asia -Trip by RPM to Asia, including SE Asia Theological Seminary Librarians Workshop in the Philippines (Box 14, Folder 181)
  - YMCA-National Council Committee on History and Library (includes Mott Biography material), 1963-1970 (Box 14, Folder 182)
  - YMCA -National Council Committee on History and Library, 1971-1975 (Box 14, Folder 183)
  - Wesley Foundation at Yale, 1949 (Box 14, Folder 184)
  - Miscellaneous collected material (Box 14, Folder 185)
- Biographical Material, Series IV
  - Graduation photo and letter, 1923 (Box 14, Folder 186)
  - Photo of Eva Kelly, mother of Jean Kelly Morris, 1935 (Box 14, Folder 187)
  - Advertisement for home talent play - RPM actor, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 187)
  - Photos of RPM. Also sketch of RPM by R. Bainton, 1952 (Box 14, Folder 188)
  - Photos of RPM in groups, 1965-1967, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 201)
  - Baker University commencement and alumni pamphlets, 1952-1976 (Box 14, Folder 189)
  - Clyde Morris will, letters, and photo. Also, newsclipping of Gussie L. Morris, 1953-1967 (Box 14, Folder 190)
  - Travel plans and itineraries. (includes unidentified photos), 1958-1961 (Box 14, Folder 191)
  - Newsclippings and biographical sketches of RPM, 1965-1972 (Box 14, Folder 192)
  - Commission on Arts in Connecticut - letters by Jean Morris to various CT and U.S. legislators, 1977-1983 (Box 14, Folder 193)
  - Service of remembrance at YDS and obituary from Yale Library Staff Newsletter, 1990 (Box 14, Folder 194)
  - Five audio cassette tapes including reminiscences of Jean Morris, 1994 (Box 14, Folder 195)
  - Scrapbook: Library staff past and present, presented May 19, 1972 to Raymond P. Morris, Librarian, Yale Divinity School, 1932-1972. (Box OV1)
  - Letterbook: A salute to Jean and Raymond P. Morris from members and friends of the American Theological Library Association, June 1972. (Box OV2)